I am an educator and engineer with 10 years of experience delivering technical content for live training, e-learning and documentation. I excel at breaking complex challenges into manageable, well-ordered chunks for engineers to grasp. My recent areas of expertise include full-stack web development, AWS architecture, single-page apps built on JavaScript, Angular and Node.js, data analytics, distributed computing and storage, Linux, SQL, and database schema. My goal is to work with a team I love; work on products that excite me and have a positive impact; and learn continuously.

Professional Experience

productOps, Software Engineer & Team Lead, 2014 - 2019

- Lead development, test, and release efforts using Agile practices and daily scrum. Facilitated exploration conversations at all levels, from database schema with engineers to product strategy with clients.
- Improved company culture and productivity Mentored new employees to accelerate ramp-up time.
 Facilitated engineering "book club" tackling software engineering topics one chapter-per-week.
 Developed & delivered new-hire trainings to cement the company's collaborative engineering culture.
- Built web apps and SaaS plugins with Angular front-end and Node.js Express back-end. Participated in code reviews.
- Learned whatever tools necessary from project to project to deliver quality software on time.
- Developed best practices for browser testing, integration testing, and git VCS merge process.

Looker Data Sciences, Data Analyst Writer, 2014

- Developed and delivered virtual class on programming LookML, a language for modeling SQL databases.
- Managed all documentation for Looker BI analytics software, including the LookML language spec.
- Managed transition of docs platform to Statamic CMS to improve maintainability and agility.

MapR Technologies, Sr. Curriculum Developer and Content Creator, 2012 - 2014

- Created curriculum for Apache HBase NoSQL database, including Java programming labs.
- Assisted in curriculum design and review for Java-based MapReduce programming course.
- Developed class lab environment in AWS to spin up/down 10-node Hadoop clusters on demand.
- Managed on-boarding and ramp-up plans for 6 new hires to MapR's education team.
- Researched and wrote technical documentation for all aspects of MapR's Hadoop distribution.
- Wrote Confluence Wiki plug-ins to programmatically render docs pages.

Marichiba Consulting, Web Developer & Project Manager, 2008 to 2012

Managed web content and development projects for clients lacking time, capacity, or know-how.

- MobileMakerz Prototyped mobile mini-apps for restaurants, implemented with jQuery Mobile.
 Interviewed customers to gather requirements, and generated sales and marketing material.
- Hunter Finnell Media Designed and developed website and WordPress blog, showcasing the company's services with rich embedded video. Wrote all web copy. Administered the website and YouTube channel.
- In3 Finance Designed and developed website. Turned around a complete website in under three weeks, focusing on polished, established image for a financial services company.

Education

Bachelor of Computer Engineering and Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

University of Minnesota, Duluth – Graduated magna cum laude. Minor in Mathematics.

MBA in Sustainable Management

Presidio School of Management, San Francisco, CA